Chandrabhatta Sriram

LinkedIn: linkedin.com/in/chsriram

Github: github.com/Ch-sriram

✓

Profile

Professional software engineer having 2.5+ years of experience in designing, developing & shipping software products across web, desktop & command-line. My expertise includes Full-Stack Web Development, Data Structures, Algorithms, Distributed Systems & System Design. I also like to give back to the community by teaching technical courses like Programming & DSA.

SKILLS SUMMARY

• Programming Languages: javascript/typescript, html, css, python, java, c/c++ & shell-scripting.

• Front/Back-End Frameworks: react, redux, nodejs/express, sql & mongodb.

• Testing Frameworks:

well-versed — react-testing-library, jest, enzyme, storybook & chrome-devtools. familiar-with — selenium & cucumber.

• Development Tools: git/github, jira & jupyter-notebooks.

• Platform & DevOps Tools: ansible-playbooks, github-actions & docker-containers.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Instructor

Hyderabad, India

Self Employed

Jan 2022 - Present

Email: sriram.ch1995@gmail.com

Mobile: +91 8187824990

 \circ Instructed engineering students & took classes on *C-Programming*, *Data Structures & Algorithms*, and *Object Programming using Java* with a primary focus on imparting industry-ready skills to the students.

Software Engineer II

Hyderabad, India

Zessta Software Services

Jul 2021 - Present

- Sandboxed and secured back-end compilation and runs for c, c++, c#, java, python, php & golang. This added a layer of security which does not let the user access and harm the server directly through malicious code. This feature was added using shell scripting & adding a controller using nodejs/express.
- Designed and modelled the database for adding test-cases for different type of questions (eg. multiple-choice & coding-type). Also added auto-evaluation of questions against the added test-cases. Developed using nodejs/express, mongodb & react.
- Added a dev-feature for automating git branching using python, shell-scripting & powershell-scripting.
- Wrote a RegEx library for validating OCI compliant URIs, thereby decreasing the error rate of submitting an incorrect docker image URI by 50%. The library helped in detecting docker image URIs which are OCI non-compliant prior the posting of the URI to back-end.
- Wrote a custom version auto-filler for zendesk user-support using javascript inside a scala template.
- Used localStorage & sessionStorage APIs to persist user menu selections in a workspace session.
- $\circ \ \ \textbf{Maintain \& upgrade front-end packages} \ \text{like} \ \textit{antd, typescript, lodash} \ \text{using} \ \textit{yarn package manager}.$
- Worked on component refactor by converting them to micro-frontend components, fixed bugs and optimised API calls by decreasing API calls on component renders. These fixes sometimes increased component efficiency by 200%.
- o Took mentorship sessions for junior developers on good coding practices. Helped improve code quality by getting involved in design (back-end/ui) discussions, product discussions & code-reviews.

Software Engineer I

Hyderabad, India

Zessta Software Services

Jul 2020 - Jun 2021

- Developed a launcher for running jobs written in *python*, *r*, *bash* & *scala* for performing analytics on data. The launcher supports data sources & external data volumes added by user. For additional compute power, compute clusters like *spark*, *ray* or *dask* can be used.
- $\circ \ \ \mathbf{Upgrade} \ \mathbf{front\text{-}end} \ \mathbf{legacy} \ \mathbf{packages} \ \mathbf{viz}. \ \mathit{typescript}, \ \mathit{jQuery}, \ \mathit{styled\text{-}components}, \ \mathit{axios}, \ \mathbf{etc}.$
- Worked on analysing front-end auth flow, fixing name issues & cross-browser compatibility of components, fixing workspace uptime synchronisation, etc.
- Developed a dashboard for displaying information regarding aqua-culture yield and business development employee targets. The dashboard also allows download of data to a CSV file by filtering the data through a selection of a range of dates.

Technical Content Writer (Internship)

Hyderabad, India

Smart Interviews

Feb 2018 - Sep 2018

- o Developed manuals/revision-material regarding complexity analysis where a detailed mathematical analysis of algorithms was done on the basis of Big-O, Big- Θ & Big- Ω .
- Also developed & wrote manual on string manipulation/matching in which some algorithms like Rabin Karp's & Knuth-Morris-Pratt's string matching algorithms were explored/explained in-detail.

PROJECTS

- GitHub Repo: Problem Solving Using Data Structures & Algorithms: Solved Problems on Arrays, Stacks, Queues, Lists, Trees, Hashing, Heaps, Recursion, Dynamic Programming, Greedy Paradigm, Bit Manipulation & Strings. RepoLink
- Backend Development using NodeJS (Express), SQL & MongoDB: Have a strong conceptual understanding of Middlewares, View Engines, Templating Engines, Routing, Data Modelling and Code Organisation using Express. RepoLink

EDUCATION

Osmania University
Hyderabad, India

Bachelor of Engineering - Computer Science & Engineering

 $Dec\ 2018$